Murderers are made, not born.
Crazy, Not Insane is a documentary film directed by Alex Gibney.
Fascinated by the human brain and its capacity
for ruthlessness, psychiatrist Dr.
Dorothy Otnow Lewis has spent her life investigating
the interior lives of violent people.
With each case, she came closer to developing a unified
field theory of what makes a killer.
Along the way - steering away from the conventional wisdom of her colleagues
- she explored the world of multiple personality disorder.
Self, played by Dorothy Lewis.
Literary Voice of Dorothy Lewis (voice), played by Laura Dern.
Self - Dorothy's Son, played by Eric Lewis.
Self - Dorothy's Daughter, played by Gillian Lewis.
Self - Defense Attorney, played by Richard Burr.
Self - Former FBI Special Agent, played by Bill Hagmaier.
Crazy, Not Insane is a 2020 American documentary film
directed and produced by Alex Gibney.
It follows the research of psychiatrist Dr.
Dorothy Otnow Lewis who studied the psychology of murders.
It is narrated by Laura Dern.
The film had its world premiere at Copenhagen International
Documentary Festival (CPH:DOX) on March 18, 2020.
It was released on November 18, 2020, by HBO.
The film explores themes of serial killer, murderer, psychiatrist,
dissociative identity disorder, traumatized child.
The tone is dark.